What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Portfolio range, about $420.
What's that?
$420 million.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
The insurance brokerage firm that I
run now is a multi-billion dollar company.
In industrial real estate.
We basically set out to redefine champagne.
What's your best advice to anybody
trying to own a Lamborghini like you?
Houston, Texas is the number eight city
in the world with the most millionaires.
Today, we're going to be asking
Houston millionaires how they became wealthy.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I run a company and
I solve a lot of problems.
The insurance brokerage firm that I
run now is a multi-billion dollar company.
It's crushing it and it's all
about great leadership and great people.
If you were to go back
to when you started that first business,
what's the number one thing that you would tell yourself?
Be bold and mighty forces will come to your aid.
If you can get some
education behind you, get some foundation.
And young people, they all want to try
to make it as fast as they can.
Spend four or five years understanding your discipline
and then go out and do it yourself.
What's the best financial advice that
you ever received throughout your lifetime?
Read the wealthy barber and read the millionaire next door.
And save money early in your career.
You know the rule of
seven, save 10 to 20 percent.
And if you do that by
30 or 40, you're a millionaire.
Even if you make 70, $80,000 a year.
How old were you when you first became a millionaire?
I think I was 28.
28. And how old are you now?
What's the greatest lesson that you've
learned over that period of time?
Two.
To always change people's lives, help people.
I have a 501c.
I give away a lot of money.
I love to help people.
God put me on this earth to change people's lives.
Thank you so much for your time.
I really appreciate that.
Let's go.
So where does that go?
The School of Hard Knocks, sir.
The School of Hard Knocks.
I just went up to a table full of guys at a nice
restaurant out here in one of the wealthiest areas in all of Houston.
And the guy said that he's finishing
up eating to come back in 10 minutes.
So we're going to go get an interview with him and
see how he was able to become wealthy out in Houston, Texas.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
The funny thing, oil and gas
is what I originally started off at.
I went to school.
I went to TCU.
And then I went to Rice University.
But I started off in oil
and gas as a project manager.
From being a project manager,
starting off as an angel investor.
And then from an angel investor, I had
a few successful exits, or quite a few.
Then I started my own private equity firm.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
So it's not really based on your
dividends, what you make off of, your companies.
It's more of what do you
have as far as your portfolio.
So portfolio range, about $420.
What's that?
$420 million.
What was the biggest risk that
you ever took throughout your career?
Snapchat was.
How so?
Because they were raising their seed round in 2010.
And I ended up investing pretty
much everything as a project manager.
My salary, $80,000 at that time.
That was a lot.
So someone asking for $20,000 of your money.
And you're like, that's a lot of
money to just pay out of pocket.
That was a big risk.
But I mean, it paid off.
How much did you ultimately make off Snapchat?
So I was a board member of Snap.
I actually retired about three years ago.
So I mean, from just Snap and all
the other companies in my portfolio, probably about $72.
$72 million?
Yeah.
What is the biggest thing in your portfolio?
In your opinion, that takes a business
from seven to eight and eventually nine figures?
Marketing.
I mean, marketing is going to be
your number one thing you ask any investor.
They're going to tell you marketing.
I can sell shit, literally.
And people will buy it.
Mind you, it might not be everyone that'll buy it.
But if I market it right, there will be
hundreds of millions of people that actually invest into that.
Your portfolio was valued at $400 million?
Correct.
What's the best financial advice
you've ever received throughout your career?
Figure out loopholes.
When you're buying something, don't
buy it directly under yourself.
Always buy your assets under other
entities, holdings and things of that sort.
Lease it to yourself.
Two write-offs right there.
I just told you.
So many different loopholes, but the
main thing is to keep your money.
Figure out those loopholes, understand
them, and be smart with it.
We just interviewed right there.
You can tell he's worked with
a lot of crazy people and connections.
It's all about who you know.
You've got to invest with people that are wealthier than you,
that you know, and that's how you rise to the top.
That's how you make the success.
That right there was just the
number one use case of it.
He's got a portfolio with over $400 million, and you just
know that the people that he's worked with and connected with,
to find those companies, find those deals, get in those
rooms, were able to help him achieve a nine-figure net worth.
How old were you when you made your first million?
I don't know.
Probably 10 years ago.
What is the blueprint to
becoming a millionaire in today's world?
When I was a young kid, they always told me.
I didn't understand it.
They said 90% of success is showing up.
And today I understand that because if you show up to
work, not only do you get work done, but people trust you.
They know you're going to be there at like clockwork.
And in today's society, showing up is the key.
Show up, bust your ass, be the best worker.
And most people today, when they
invest, they don't invest in businesses.
They invest in people.
So that's my shortcut.
There's hundreds of restaurants throughout Houston.
What's the biggest thing that you've documented throughout
your business to really stand apart from the competition?
Details.
Remembering kids' names, having birthday
cakes for people, surprising them.
Little details.
Handwritten letters.
Thank you for coming in the restaurant.
Those things set you apart from everybody else.
Can you just kind of explain to them how many people came up and
talked to you about the interview you did a few months ago in Houston?
Well, I didn't know you guys were like national news.
I thought it was just a little thing
for a class at University of Houston or something.
But I had maybe 150,
200 people come up to me.
Oh my God, I learned so much from
that little three minute video or two minute video.
But you guys are good at what you do.
So just keep it up.
Thank you so much.
Pleasure.
We really appreciate that time.
Where can everybody find you?
Prosperity19, man.
I'm always here 24-7.
We'll give you guys some real game.
You're always used to seeing us
interview people, asking multimillionaires for the game.
Here's the game.
Like and subscribe to the School of Hard Knocks.
You heard it here first.
We're on a mission to be the best
educational and finance channel in the entirety of YouTube.
So if you're not subscribed, you're not
going to get a chance to do that.
If you're not a supporter already,
come on, what are you doing?
Have you ever been a business
owner at any point in time?
I have.
The restaurant industry with my former husband.
What's your best advice to anybody
starting a business in today's world?
I would just say, you know, I think
a lot of people, they doubt themselves too much.
And the ones that don't, the ones that get up every day
and don't take no for an answer and still believe in themselves.
Yeah.
You can do anything you want to do.
What's the best financial advice
you ever received throughout your lifetime?
Take care of your pennies and
the dollars will take care of themselves.
My grandmother.
My grandmother told me that.
I love that.
Look at who's going in the Lamborghini.
She just gave some great game.
Check her out.
What's your best advice to anybody
trying to own a Lamborghini like you?
Put it out into the universe and you'll get it.
Yeah?
Yeah, definitely.
That's why I was telling you, anything.
You can really create and have anything.
Put it out in the universe, visualize it, see
it, and just go after it and don't give
up on it.
Absolutely.
Thank you guys so much for your time.
Have a great day, guys.
Thank you.
And she came and delivered to us some great value.
She was a business owner in the restaurant
industry and how she was able to really grow
and become a successful business owner and how
you can get a Lamborghini in today's world.
She pulled up here in a Lamborghini.
So let's go get some more out in Houston.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
My degree is engineering.
The industry I'm in is I build
port infrastructure equipment, so docking and mooring equipment
for big port facilities.
I get to travel around the world and
tell people how to basically manage issues and
overcome obstacles.
What's the best piece of advice?
piece of advice that you would tell your younger
self? So I think when we're born you basically are
given a ledger of numbers and all those
numbers are associated with decisions you get to make
and those decisions actually on the front end so
like one through fifty when you become like a
human being and like you actually can
make decisions for yourself they compound meaning
like if you make some really horrible decisions as
a young at a young age they can cascade
throughout your life but as you get older they get
more valuable so I mean I think decision making is
probably one of the most important things that
you need to consider. What's the best advice that
you ever received from a mentor? It came from my
dad my dad's a stud too it's being genuine but
at the same time being a chameleon so we all
have to adapt to the situations that are present and
you have to be able to adapt in a genuine
way where you're not lying to anybody but you can
still fit in and you can be approachable
most people that become successful they either go on
the narcissistic path or they go on the
altruistic path and and they would rather probably help
up and just be able to get out of the
situation and be able to be more comfortable with their life.
I'm not trying to gravitate towards others than themselves I'm I
try to gravitate towards not being the biggest person in the room.
Thank you so much for your time I really appreciate
that I loved your answers. I gotta say this Houston
video may be one of my favorite ones I've
ever shot. River Oaks is one of the wealthiest areas
and centers in all of Houston. We're out
here we've been snagging interviews all day so let's
keep them coming. In what industry did you
ultimately pursue a career? In industrial real estate.
Are you a business owner? Yeah. What exactly do
you what exactly do you do what is your company?
We buy or build and lease large industrial
properties all over the country. What's been the most
amount of money that you ever made in a single
year? Over a million dollars. What's been your
secret to being able to scale your business in
real estate? Secret is working 60 hours a
week. What's been your secret to sales throughout your
career? Best way to close deals is to listen.
Don't be the person talking the entire time because
you don't understand their perspectives and their needs
and their wants and then you know how to
fulfill those needs and wants and you get the
sale and you'll get the sale the next time.
Absolutely. Thank you so much for
your time I really appreciate it.
Thank you. I appreciate you taking the
time to meet with us. Thank you Sarah.
What's the best piece of advice you would tell
your younger self? Live your best life always and
don't worry about the future. What industry did
you ultimately pursue a career in? Social media
marketing for a renewable energy company. What's
the secret to marketing building a strong brand?
Networking and building relationships outside of
social media platforms. What's been the most
amount of money that you ever made in a
single year? Probably 350 to half a million a year.
What's the best financial advice you ever received?
Learn the importance of saving early on and invest
as soon as you can. Real estate property is a great
way to save money. It's a great way to save money.
Real estate properties you know building them up
are a good investment option I guess early on
and then later on investing in companies that are worth
a while. Thank you so much for your time I
really appreciate that the channel is this you want it
I'll get you I got you let's do it. What
industry did you pursue a career in? Real
estate investment trusts. What's the biggest deal that
you've ever closed in real estate? 1.2 million and it
has to do with the businesses and all the tax
breaks that you get along with it. It's not just like
cash up front but it has to do with all the
tax breaks you're getting and all of the cash
that you're getting. So I think it's really important
to have a real estate investment trust. Because you're
going to have to make a lot of money
and you're going to have to make a lot of money.
So I think it's really important to have a real estate
investment trust. Because you're going to have to make
a lot of money. So I think it's really important
to have a real estate investment trust. Because you're going
to have to make a lot of money. And all
of the caveats and the nuances from that.
What's your best investment advice for people looking to
buy property? Do your research on what are
the caveats for real estate investment so it's not
just what you learn in real estate school. But you
have to find out about the tax breaks and things
that are going to make you a millionaire that most
people don't do. And one more thing be sure to like
and follow the school of hard knocks. What
industry did you ultimately pursue a career in? Actually
the champagne space. Are you a business owner?
Yeah. What inspired you to really start a business
in this industry? I'm a business owner. I'm a
business owner. I'm a business owner. I'm a business
owner. I'm a business owner. I'm a business owner. I'm a business owner. I'm a business owner. This is a passion that I had going back to 22 years ago when I was in the restaurant industry. And I pursued that in oil and gas.
Traveling the world and essentially seeing all the great places in the world for wine. All the great terroirs. So specifically I just continued to learn and evolve with wine. And then I was able to basically turn my passion into a real business case.
What's been your secret to sales throughout your career? How have you been able to sell your product at
a high volume over the last few years? I think it's really twofold. I think it's all about relationships.
It's all about being genuine. And it's also about having a product that is essentially second to none. It's something truly special. Where you can go up against the conglomerates that have a
lot of other things working for them, but they don't have the relationships. They're hiding behind a big label. And ultimately they don't really share that passion and the quality isn't there as well.
So you were kind of like an innovator within that niche itself. Oh absolutely. And so what's your advice to someone who
is trying to find that winning product in the niche or the market that they're in? Do as much research as you can.
Do as much research as you can.
board know your market know your competitors know
your price point of the market know if you're
premium what what that means what you can dictate
in terms of price make sure you nail your margins
down spend as much time as you can don't think
you can wing it and then you're going to always
end up on top because at the end of the
day you always come out with costs that are higher than
what you expect so set contingencies in but
firstly do all the research you can possibly do
thank you guys so much for watching this video
and click right here to watch us going all around
miami asking multi-millionaires how they became successful